# **NEIL LIBERMAN**

## Data Scientist

#### **ABOUT**

Background in economics and statistics to accompany proficiency with Python. Have worked on real world problems implementing supervised and unsupervised machine learning models. Driven by an unrelenting desire to improve my technical proficiency and help influence outcomes of positive change.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## General Assembly, Washington, DC

Data Science Immersive | Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- 700+ hours of data science training including 40 labs and 6 projects.
- Strong emphasis on both supervised and unsupervised machine learning models which include linear and logistic regression, support vector machines, random forests, K Nearest Neighbors, DBSCAN, K Means Clustering, amongst others.
- Additional focus on statistics and linear algebra to provide a core understanding for models used.

## **Keyes Law Firm, LLC,** Baltimore, MD — Finance and Administration

Feb. 2012 - Nov. 2016

- Contributed to designing the company's settlement tracking system in excel.
- Scoured records to find unrecouped funds from partner law firms.
- Communicated with co-counsel daily to handle administrative tasks and unresolved issues.
- Took initiative to resolve many tracking flaws and information transfer issues the firm had implemented before my arrival. This included pushing to implement an ftp file transfer system.

#### **EDUCATION**

## General Assembly, Washington, DC

Data Science Immersive | Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

## University of Maryland, College Park

B.A. Economics | 2008-2012

Baltimore, MD 443-797-7840 neil.liberman@gmail.com github.com/nliberman/projects medium.com/@neil.liberman

#### **SKILLS**

Python

SQL

**Pandas** 

Machine Learning

Tableau

Git

Web Scraping

Natural Language Processing

#### **DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS**

Basketball Analytics scraped NBA data to find correlations to offensive efficiency, leading to conclusion on optimal shot locations and player development goals.

Iowa Liquor Sales used liquor, population, and income data to advise where an entrepreneur would be best served to open a liquor store.

Data Science Salaries scraped data science salaries to determine which keywords are most predictive of high salaries.

West Nile Virus used weather data to predict which mosquito traps in Chicago would contain West Nile Virus.

Bayesian Analysis of Terrorism used bayesian analysis to compare two South American populations.